American Labor Education Service Additional Documents 5657
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Labor Education Service Additional Documents
1929-1965
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
American Labor Education Service (ALES)
5657
1 cubic feet
1 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Labor and worker education documents
5685208
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, January 20, 2016
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, March 25, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5225: ALES Records 5225 C: ALES Course Materials 5225 E: ALES Labor Education Records 5225 I: ALES International Labor Records 5225 L: ALES Labor Plays 5225 S: ALES Scrapbooks
American Labor Education Service
5685208
- Labor Education - General, 1935-1956 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  Scope and Contents
  Educational Methods in Teaching Workers (1935), American Workers' Education (1936), Planning a Local Union Education Program, Understanding Industrial and Labor Relations (1948), The ARMY and Labor (1948), "Keep Them Free" (1951) and Labor Education Study Report (1956)
- Labor Education- General, 1934-1953 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  Pamphlets, Announcements and Booklets from Various University Offerings on Industrial and Labor Management Relations
- Labor Education - Local, 1934-1964 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Conference Summaries, Report Issues, Publications and Surveys by Various University Programs
- Worker's Education Bureau, 1932-1956 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  Press Pamphlets, Labor Series Lectures and News Letters
- Unions - General, 1929-1965 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  Union Hand Books, Seminars and University Brochures
- Foreign Workers' Schools, 1938-1956 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  Information Booklets on International Students and Schools
- Highlander Folk School, 1946-1957 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  Articles and Newspaper Clippings to do with the Highlander Folk School
- ALES, 1936-1962 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  Labor Education Guides, Study Notes, Annual Reports and Papers for American Labor Education Service
- Investigation of Tax Exempt Foundations re. ALES, 1954 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  8/20/1954 Staff Report
- AFT Local 189, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  Brochures, Publication Issues, Constitution and Meeting Minutes of American Federations of Teachers Under AFL-CIO